Welcome... to the Qocent FinOps Platform. The only
cost management solution... purpose-built... for Huawei Cloud Stack.
This... is your Overview Dashboard. Right at the top, four KPI cards tell you everything you need to know. Total spend month-to-date... budget
utilization... active resources... and potential savings. And below that? A cost trend chart, with thirty days of history, and a seven-day AI-powered forecast.
Now let's talk about Cost Analytics. You can slice your spending five different ways. By service... by
region... by tenant... and over time. The comparison tab lets you benchmark across periods, tenants, or regions.
Here's your Resources module. Every cloud resource, organized inside Virtual Data Centers... exactly
the way HCS structures them. CPU, memory, network, and disk utilization... right alongside cost.
Recommendations. Your optimization command center. Six categories. Rightsizing... idle resources... storage... network...
reserved capacity... and database tuning. Every recommendation shows estimated savings and confidence score.
And the history tab... tracks every action you've
taken. Easy wins can be implemented with one click.
Tenant Management. Every tenant at a glance...
spend, resource count, efficiency score, and budget status.
Click into any tenant... and you get the full picture. Resources,
cost trends, activity logs, and access visibility across the entire VDC hierarchy.
Tag Governance. Create tag groups with enforced data types. The compliance dashboard shows
your tagging score... highlights missing required tags... and tracks violations across every tenant.
Budget Management. Set budgets at any level... tenant, VDC, or zone. Green means on track. Amber
means at risk. Red... means you've gone over. Progress bars and percentages give you instant clarity.
Cost Allocation. Two treemap visualizations, side by side. Service costs on the left... tenant costs on the right.
The bigger the block... the bigger the spend. You see exactly where your money is going, at a glance.
Reports. Nine pre-built types... plus a custom report builder. Schedule them daily, weekly,
or monthly. Export to CSV, PDF, or Excel. Share directly with your stakeholders.
Waste Detection. This module finds money you're leaving on the table. Idle compute... orphaned
storage... unused network resources. Every resource gets a waste score from zero to a hundred.
Notifications. Budget alerts... cost anomalies... optimization recommendations. All
organized by severity. Filter by category or read status.
The Support Center. Three channels in one module. Submit tickets... chat live
with human agents... or pick up the phone with twenty-four seven coverage.
The HCS Architecture Guide. An interactive diagram of the full Cloud
Stack hierarchy. ManageOne... zones... tenants... and five levels of Virtual Data Centers.
And finally... Settings. Profile, currency, language. The Users tab for role-based
access. API Keys to connect Huawei Cloud. And Security for two-factor authentication.
Oh... and everything you've just seen? Works beautifully... in dark mode. Two hundred and eighteen features. Fourteen
modules. Built for Huawei Cloud Stack. Built for Africa. Built for enterprise. This... is the Qocent FinOps Platform.